Hello it's Scott Manley here.
你好 我是Scott Manley
Back from Hawaii and it is the tenth anniversary of the release of Kerbal Space Program,
我从夏威夷回来 今天是《Kerbal Space Program》发行十周年
a game which well if you watch me you probably know about
如果你看了我的节目 你可能知道这个游戏
but if you don't before I talked about real rockets all the time
但如果你不知道 在我一直在谈论真正的火箭之前
I kind of started playing video games with video game rockets.
我开始用电子游戏中的火箭来玩电子游戏
And Kerbal Space Program was the game that can put me out there.
而《Kerbal Space Program》是能让我出场的游戏
Basically gave me an audience that actually made me interested in talking about these things.
基本上给了我一个听众 使我对谈论这些事情真正感兴趣
So Kerbal Space Program was originally released on June 24th 2011.
所以Kerbal Space Program最初是在2011年6月24日发布的
That was just less than a month I think before the final launch of the space Shuttle.
我想那是在航天飞机最终发射前不到一个月的时间
The very earliest alpha release was Version 0.7.3.
最早的alpha版本是0.7.3版
And it had these little green men which turned out to be a great selling factor/
它有这些小绿人 这变成了一个伟大的销售因素/
I know like the physics is great. The rocket science is fantastic.
我知道像物理学是伟大的 火箭科学非常棒
But having three little green men in the bottom right corner of your screen
但是在你的屏幕右下角有三个小绿人
screaming whenever anything explodes really made it stick with a lot more gamers.
每当有东西爆炸时 就会有三个小绿人在你的屏幕右下角尖叫 这真的让更多的游戏玩家坚持下去
The version we have here has a very simple space center.
我们这里的版本有一个非常简单的空间中心
The only thing you can click on is the vehicle assembly building.
你可以点击的唯一东西是车辆装配大楼
This is after all an alpha release,
这毕竟是一个alpha版本
six months after they started developing the game.
在他们开始开发游戏六个月后
So you have a very familiar looking screen here.
所以你在这里有一个非常熟悉的屏幕
A lot of the same icons.
很多相同的图标
You can click on your various parts.
你可以点击你的各种零件
Interestingly they have decals which didn't actually turn up in the game until about a year ago.
有趣的是 他们有贴花 直到一年前才真正出现在游戏中
But you have a little command pod there.
但你有一个小小的指挥舱
And you could start assembling bits on it.
而且你可以开始在上面组装零件
So put a stack decoupler under there.
所以在那下面放一个堆栈式解耦器
Put ourselves Rocket engine.
把我们自己的火箭发动机
And underneath that well we probably need to move the whole thing upward.
而在这下面 我们可能需要把整个东西往上移
Well at least that works.
好吧 至少这样可以了
There's a lot of stuff in this that you expect to work if you've played the game
如果你玩过这个游戏 你就会觉得这里面有很多东西是可以用的
which doesn't actually work because it wasn't implemented.
但实际上并不工作 因为它没有被实现
Let's put an FL-T500 in here.
让我们把一个FL-T500放在这里
Now you'll notice I'm doing one tank here and not multiple tanks.
现在你会注意到我在这里做一个坦克 而不是多个坦克
The reason is back in this very earliest version only one tank could feed one engine.
原因是在这个最早期的版本中 只有一个坦克可以为一个引擎提供能量
So you couldn't stack tanks the way that we're all used to these days.
因此 你不能像我们现在所习惯的那样堆放坦克
Let's do this.
让我们来做这个
And we'll do another tank.
我们再做一个坦克
And we'll also try to put some Radial boosters on right?
我们还将尝试安装一些径向助推器 对吗？
So Radial decouplers are things you attached to the side.
辐射式助推器是你连接到侧面的东西
And in this version there's no symmetry.
在这个版本中 没有对称性
You just have to sort of guess where it is and slap them on there.
你只需要猜测它的位置 然后把它们拍在上面
And hope that they are lined up sufficiently well
并希望它们能充分地排好队
that they don't actually spin you off and cause you to fall over.
以免它们把你甩出去 导致你摔倒
There are also little fins there
那里还有一些小鳍
but those don't actually work as control surfaces.
但那些实际上并不作为控制面工作
They don't move. They don't actuate.
它们不移动 它们不启动
And again of course you have to worry about symmetry.
当然 你还得担心对称性问题
No aerodynamic nosecone
没有空气动力鼻锥
because well the aerodynamics in this game are very primitive at this time
因为这个游戏的空气动力学在这个时候是非常原始的
so I can actually adjust the staging here which is great.
所以我实际上可以调整这里的分期 这很好
One thing I haven't put on is the parachute,
有一件事我还没有装上 那就是降落伞
and you'll notice in the description that it still has that comedic outlook on life.
你会注意到在描述中 它仍然有那种喜剧性的人生观
Widely accepted this is a better alternative to being in free fall.
广泛接受这是比自由落体更好的选择
Okay. I'm gonna see if this thing actually flies. It probably won't.
好吧 我要看看这东西是否真的能飞起来 它可能不会
It could well crash.
它很可能会坠毁
And so here we are on the launch pad.
所以我们现在在发射台上
And you'll notice by the way if you're a regular player
你会注意到 如果你是一个普通的玩家
that we have this massive launch tower here.
我们这里有一个巨大的发射塔
That was in all the early versions.
那是在所有早期的版本中
It was eventually removed.
它最终被移除
Because players began building rockets so large that they would just clip through that tower and explode on spawning.
因为玩家们开始把火箭造得太大了 以至于它们会直接穿过发射塔并在产卵时爆炸
Now. I remember actually an early version where one of the things I did
现在 我记得在早期的版本中 我做的一件事是
was lift off and try to land on top of that.
是升空并试图降落在那上面
So the landscape is still procedureally generated,
所以景观仍然是按程序生成的
although you'll notice there's a lot of like giggle as a terrain. RE renders at different detail levels,
尽管你会注意到有很多像傻笑一样的地形 RE在不同的细节水平上进行渲染
obviously that got improved a whole lot,
显然 这一点得到了很大的改善
but yeah um Look at those boosters on the outside
但是 嗯 看看外面的那些助推器
straining against their Radial mounts.
对他们的径向支架的压力
That soft joint physics. Was very much core to the Kerbal design.
那个软关节物理学 这是Kerbal设计的核心
In fact I think the very first internal build of Kerbal space program
事实上 我认为Kerbal太空计划的第一个内部版本就有这个功能
had the. Boosters fly up for a couple of seconds and then sheer off due to excess stress.
有 助推器飞了几秒钟 然后由于过度的压力而脱落
You'll notice that we do actually have fuel gauges for the solar dropic boosters not for the regular engine.
你会注意到 我们确实为太阳能落地式助推器配备了燃料表 而不是为普通发动机配备
We have no idea what's going on.
我们不知道发生了什么事
Also one of the sort of original game design features
另外 游戏的一个原始设计特点是
was supposed to be flying as high as possible before your rocket overheated.
应该是在你的火箭过热之前尽可能地飞得高
That Ken had stopped being a thing until now,
直到现在 这肯能已经不再是一个东西了
and it would be a long time before. Thermal control became a core part of the game that had been properly designed.
而且这将是一个很长的时间 热控制成为游戏的一个核心部分 已经被正确设计
Look we stage those off and they drop back to earth to land on some Kerbal villagers,
看 我们把这些东西送上舞台 然后它们落回地球 降落在一些Kerbal村民身上
except of course in this version of Kerbal Space program
当然 在这个版本的Kerbal太空计划中
there were no villages or cities anywhere else on the planet.
地球上没有任何其他的村庄或城市
And indeed in the most recent version there are no other cities or villages anywhere else on the planet.
而事实上 在最新的版本中 地球上也没有其他的城市或村庄
At this point the planet didn't have a name.
在这一点上 这个星球还没有名字
Many people called it Kearth after with a K,
许多人称它为Kearth 以K开头
but ultimately it would become known as Kerbin.
但最终它还是被称为Kerbin
And with this early alpha of Kerbal Space Program was downloaded 5000 times and played by people like me.
就这样 Kerbal Space Program的早期alpha版本被下载了5000次 并被像我这样的人玩过
And it basically got itself a following very quickly it was developed,
而且它基本上很快就有了自己的追随者 它被开发出来
it would be several years before they released the 1.0 version,
在他们发布1.0版本之前 已经过了好几年
but there was always things to do and and always things to learn.
但总是有事情要做 总是有事情要学
Still there's lots of fun stuff to see in this early version.
在这个早期版本中 仍然有很多有趣的东西可以看
First of all you'll notice the camera is shaking around.
首先 你会注意到相机在晃动
That's an early version of the Kraken
那是早期版本的Kraken
where floating point math leads to all sorts of problems with noise and forces.
的早期版本 浮点数学导致了各种噪音和力的问题
The texture on the base of this command pod is a car wheel.
这个指挥舱底座上的纹理是一个汽车轮子
You can actually see the inflation valve and what it is.
你实际上可以看到充气阀和它是什么
It's kind of hilarious.
这有点滑稽
The parachute design is practically the same as it is in the current version today.
降落伞的设计实际上和现在的版本是一样的
Now that capsule disappeared from the game
现在那个胶囊从游戏中消失了
because that when they added. Kerbals as characters that could walk around,
因为当他们加入时 Kerbals作为可以走动的角色
they had to rescale all the parts and that turned out to be too small.
他们不得不重新调整所有部件的比例 结果发现这太小了
But the capsule still exists in the game if you know where to look,
但是 如果你知道去哪里找 这个胶囊仍然存在于游戏中
so this is actually the brand new version which was just released earlier this week.
所以这实际上是本周初刚刚发布的全新版本
The main thing that ads are firework launchers because it's the tenth anniversary.
广告的主要内容是烟花发射器 因为这是十周年纪念
They add some new textures or some of the older planets.
他们增加了一些新的纹理或一些旧的行星
There's a few other items in here.
这里面还有一些其他项目
The save and load manager is completely redesigned which is great,
保存和加载管理器是完全重新设计的 这是伟大的
because you you know you play the game for a long time you end up with a lot of different spacecraft.
因为你知道你玩了很长时间的游戏 你最终会有很多不同的航天器
But this is one that is downloaded from Steam.
但这是一个从Steam下载的
So yeah you can head out off the runway towards the vehicle assembly building,
所以 是的 你可以从跑道出来 走向飞行器组装大楼
which is the big building in the middle of that massively redesigned Space Center right?
这是在那个大规模重新设计的太空中心中间的大建筑 对吗？
And just in front of it to the right of that little spherical tank.
就在它的前面 在那个小球状坦克的右边
There is a monument. A monument to the original Mark one part.
那里有一个纪念碑 一座纪念碑 纪念原来的马克一号的部分
Hewn out of solid stone which probably doesn't help with water recovery.
用坚硬的石头铸成 这可能对水的回收没有帮助
And a couple of hundred kilometers north of the desert launch site,
在沙漠发射场以北几百公里的地方
there is a small hidden valley.
有一个隐藏的小山谷
And inside that there is the old version of the launch site.
而在那里面有旧版的发射场
Although the graphics have been upgraded just a little bit
虽然图形已经被升级了一点点
to bring them up to date with the rest of the game.
以使其与游戏的其他部分保持同步
But now in the new release
但现在在新版本中
there are a number of other launch sites which have been added around Kerbin,
在Kerbin周围还增加了一些其他的发射场
and these are sort of easter eggs that you have to find
这些都是一些复活节彩蛋 你必须找到它们
and of course thankfully there's some mods to help you out with this.
当然 值得庆幸的是 有一些mods可以帮助你解决这个问题
So this is one that's actually pretty near to the launch site.
所以这是一个离发射场很近的地方
You fly up to it and you get this message at the top telling you
你飞到它面前 你会在上面看到这个信息 告诉你
you have unlocked it in the game.
你已经在游戏中解锁了它
The great thing about this one,
这个地方最棒的地方是
which is just north of launch site is that it has a ramp that goes into the water.
就在发射场的北面 它有一个斜坡 可以进入水中
Finally in well the final major release of the game,
最后 在游戏的最后一个主要版本中
we get official support for boats.
我们得到了对船只的正式支持
you don't have to fly them out to sea and drop them in the water anymore.
你不必再让它们飞到海上 然后把它们扔进水里
You can just slide them down the slipway and make them look like real ships.
你可以直接把它们从滑道上滑下来 让它们看起来像真的船
There are a few other easter eggs have been added in the final release.
还有一些其他的复活节彩蛋已经被添加到最终版本中
Here's one that was made on Kerbin by Kerbals.
这里有一个由Kerbals在Kerbin制作的
And here's me having a bit of an oopsy with opportunity.
这是我用机会做的一个小插曲
But beyond the easter eggs and the fireworks,
但除了复活节彩蛋和焰火之外 还有一些实际的游戏变化
there is some actual gameplay changes which are really good especially for new players.
还有一些实际的游戏变化 特别是对新玩家来说 这真的很好
So there's something called the maneuver tool,
因此 有一种叫做机动工具的东西
and the maneuver tool is here to help you plot courses to planets and the moons and everything.
机动工具是用来帮助你规划行星、卫星和所有东西的路线的
So you select your target it does some computation.
所以你选择你的目标 它会进行一些计算
You can create a node.
你可以创建一个节点
So if I want to go to the asteroid in the middle of asteroid belt called Dres, it's done the math.
所以 如果我想去小行星带中间的一个叫Dres的小行星 它已经做了计算
It told me that the next maneuver is in 116 days.
它告诉我 下一次演习是在116天后
You'll take 1.5 kilometers per second of Delta V to escape.
你要用每秒1.5公里的Delta V来逃跑
And 1.75 to arrive so I create it
1.75公里的速度到达 所以我创造了它
and look it's gone and created tha for me.
看 它已经走了 并为我创建了Tha
it's created a node and I can actually run account down to that and perform the maneuver.
它创建了一个节点 我可以实际运行账户并执行机动
It will also create an alarm clock a scheduling system
它还会创建一个闹钟 一个日程安排系统
so that if you have other missions doing other things,
这样 如果你有其他任务 做其他事情
it will remind you when you have maneuvers that you need to do,
它将提醒你什么时候需要进行机动操作
so this is these are features are been in mods for a long time,
所以 这些功能在mods中已经存在了很长时间了
but it's nice to see them in the core game.
但很高兴在核心游戏中看到它们
Of course the game is still entirely manual control.
当然 游戏仍然是完全手动控制
There's no autopilot.
没有自动驾驶
This is just telling you when to fire your engines in what direction to fire them in.
这只是告诉你什么时候发射你的引擎 向什么方向发射
And even then it still doesn't work for a lot of maneuvers.
即使如此 它仍然对很多机动动作不起作用
These are just for basic transfer maneuvers from circular orbits,
这些只是用于从圆形轨道的基本转移机动
around one planet to a circular orbit on another.
围绕一个星球的圆形轨道转移到另一个星球的圆形轨道
If you're in deep space then you might not be able to use it.
如果你在深空 那么你可能无法使用它
And the latest release brings a few new parts.
而最新的版本带来了一些新的部件
In the very first release of Kerbal Space Program there were eleven different parts.
在Kerbal Space Program的第一个版本中 有11个不同的零件
Now there's over 400.
现在有超过400个
This really brings four new types of solar panels.
这确实带来了四种新的太阳能电池板
These are some of them.
这些是其中的一些
There's the circular design on solar panels.
太阳能电池板上有圆形设计
You have basically four types of solar panels are now added.
你基本上有四种类型的太阳能电池板现在被添加
And the docking ports have been completely redesigned,
对接端口已经被完全重新设计了
and they now feature the ability to provide some inline rotation
他们现在的特点是能够提供一些在线旋转的能力
to make sure your parts are aligning correctly.
以确保你的部件能正确对齐
One item though that didn't make it into release was the stamp patron ground anchor.
不过 有一个项目没有进入发布阶段 那就是邮票守护者地锚
People wanted ways to anchor their hardware onto a planet's surface.
人们希望有办法将他们的硬件固定在星球的表面上
They had all sorts of cool ideas for it.
他们有各种很酷的想法
Unfortunately during testing was found that it kept on coming unstuck.
不幸的是 在测试过程中 人们发现它不断地陷入困境
and so that means that the final release of Kerbal Space Program isn't actually the final release.
因此 这意味着Kerbal Space Program的最终版本实际上并不是最终版本
There's definitely going to be a 1.12.1 release at some point in the future.
在未来的某个时间点 肯定会有一个1.12.1版本
And that will fix a few things that will probably add a few other bits and pieces that were missed,
这将修复一些事情 并可能增加一些其他被遗漏的部分
and you know what you might be wondering what happens to the team behind Kerbal Space Program.
你知道吗 你可能想知道Kerbal Space Program背后的团队会发生什么
What they're going to be doing from now on.
他们从现在开始会做什么
Well there can be working on Kerbal Space Program 2.
好吧 有可能会在《Kerbal Space Program 2》上工作
There is another team that has been working on that game for several years,
有另一个团队已经在那个游戏上工作了好几年
but it has had this released date pushed back by 2 years,
但它的发布日期被推后了两年
and frankly I'm okay with that,
坦率地说 我对此并不反对
because I prefer them to deliver a product
因为我更希望他们能提供一个产品
which captures everything that is great about Kerbal space program.
捕捉到Kerbal太空计划的一切优点
Now I could go on and on about how important Kerbal space program has been,
现在我可以继续说 Kerbal太空计划有多么重要
how it's such a your powerful educational tool,
它是如此强大的教育工具
how it has inspired many people.
它是如何启发了许多人
But I am just one person.
但我只是一个人
And over at the official channel they've actually got a many documentary called The Kerbal Effect
在官方频道上 他们实际上有一部名为《Kerbal效应》的许多纪录片
that interviews people from NASA, European Space Agency,
采访了来自美国宇航局、欧洲航天局的人
amateur rocketry of aficionados,
业余火箭的爱好者
the CEO of the United Launch Alliance.
联合发射联盟的首席执行官
Basically people who are absolutely qualified talk about space and rocket science because that is their job.
基本上那些绝对有资格谈论太空和火箭科学的人 因为那是他们的工作
And for Kerbal Space Program we've had ten amazing years of development and updates.
对于Kerbal Space Program 我们已经有了十年惊人的发展和更新
But I don't think the story ends here.
但我不认为故事到此结束
Or first of all there is one more update coming at least,
或者说 首先 至少还有一次更新的机会
and I think now that we're seeing a fixed version to work against.
我认为现在我们看到的是一个固定的版本 可以对照使用
The mod developers will finally update all their mods,
模型开发者最终会更新他们所有的模型
and we will have a glorious future of Kerbal Space program forever.
而我们将永远拥有Kerbal Space项目的辉煌未来
I'm Scott Manly. Fly safe.
我是Scott Manly 飞行安全